Daniel J. Marchetto

(412) 720-3173 dmarchetto93@gmail.com Google Scholar daniel-marchetto.github.io GitHub: daniel-marchetto LinkedIn: daniel-marchetto

Behavioral and Data Scientist. My current project involves utilizing my skills to learn the experience and motivations of graduate students on the r/GradSchool subreddit forum. This project includes topic modeling, sentiment analysis, surveying, and interviews.

EDUCATION

Master of Science in Computational Science and Engineering, Georgia Institute of Technology Specialization: Computational Social Science	2022
Master of Science in Statistics, Georgia Institute of Technology	2021
Master of Public Policy, Arizona State University	2018
Bachelor of Science in Psychology, Carnegie Mellon University	2016

PUBLICATIONS

Topic Classification of Electric Vehicle Consumer Experience with Transformer-based Deep Learning, *Patterns 2021* Ha, S., Marchetto, D.J., Dharur, S., Asensio, O.I.

Extracting User Behavior at Electric Vehicle Charging Stations with Transformer Deep Learning Models, *CARMA 2020* Marchetto, D.J., Ha, S., Dharur, S., Asensio, O.I.

RESEARCH EXPERIENCE

OECD Science & Technology Policy Hackathon

May 2022 - June 2022

- Analyzed green transition goals from 24 country S&T strategy documents utilizing a BERT-based classifier and topic model.
- Demonstrated that green transition goals present in strategies are not reflected in a country's S&T policy initiatives.

Graduate Research Assistant

August 2018 — May 2021

Dr. Julia Melkers

Georgia Tech

- Analyzed themes from phone interviews with CS graduate students to learn sources of self-efficacy.
- Designed the structure and elements of a large-scale MS CS student survey including developing a novel self-efficacy scale.
- Collected and analyzed literature relating to faculty career development and online education.

Dr. Omar Isaac Asensio Georgia Tech

- Designed and implemented survey to crowd-source partial training labels for use in BERT and XLNET topic classification task.
- Extracted and analyzed consumer dissatisfaction from unstructured EV charge station reviews using fixed-effect models in R.
- · Analyzed impact of HUD funding on household electricity consumption in Albany, GA with matching and panel models.

Smart Community Corps Fellow

May 2019 — September 2019

Institute for People and Technology

Georgia Tech

- Graduate Fellow in project to improve data connectivity and transparency in the City of Albany, GA.
- Consulted on design of SQL database for linkage of city records relating to economic development and utility consumption.
- Eased public access to city data by designing a geohub website using ESRI's web service.

Graduate Research Assistant

January 2017 — July 2018

Dr. Lily Hsueh

Arizona State

- Conducted literature search on firm-level carbon emission reduction and its relation to corporate self-governance.
- Collected firm-level emission data and Twitter data from S&P 500 corporations using Thomson Reuters and Python.
- Analyzed trends between Twitter postings and corporate emissions using classification and regression techniques in R.

Research Intern Republic Services June 2017 — August 2017

Phoenix, AZ

- Managed project to analyze sources of turnover in material recycling facilities.
- Conducted phone and on-site interviews with key stakeholders and presented results to members of upper management.

TEACHING EXPERIENCE

Co-InstructorResearch Design in Policy ScienceSpring 2022Graduate Teaching AssistantBig Data and Public PolicySpring 2020

SKILLS

Tools and Languages Analytic Techniques R, Python, Julia, SQL, Git, LTFX

Regression, Classification, Clustering, Structural Equation Modeling, Multilevel Modeling,

Experimental Design, Survey Design, Psychometrics, Text Analysis